Making it through the summer.
Uh
rally continues into all-time highs. Val
falls off sharply.
Uh the biggest question I've been asked,
and as I mentioned last week, I'm
spending a lot more time with uh RIAs.
And
also with the institutions, and the
biggest question
I received post uh let's say situational
awareness in the
the
breakdown in uh in factor val was how to
hedge AI going forward. So, I'm going to
go through that. I put together a prompt
for you guys uh
on something connected back to the uh
thematic portfolio, so you can run that.
I'm also going to start to hopefully
give you guys some stuff on agents. Uh
Gavin Baker interview, uh I'll basically
make sure uh that I emphasize this is a
must-listen to, regardless of your views
on AI. Uh I've said a lot of these
things,
but I think, as I take you through it,
um it's really important to make sure
that you at least hear what he's saying
based on a trip out to Silicon Valley.
Uh
I didn't get a chance because I record
on Fridays during the summertime most of
the time. That'll probably be the case
going forward, but
after I recorded um the US intervened in
dollar-yen, and I will uh give you my
thoughts on that because there was a
major reaction in gold this week.
And uh I think this is all going to lead
into Bitcoin, uh and I'm going to go
through why and how
what my Substack that I wrote last week
kind of connects everything back to it.
So, um last week I talked about uh
the bounce that had occurred in the
final 2 days post the
Citadel buying from situational
awareness, and how it reminded me of
prior panic situations where we finally
had a cleansing event and that you can't
especially in in the moves that we had
seen that were historic with the
volatility with the factor drop that
you had to look for follow through days
and basically what I wanted to see was
two conditions one hold the the bounce
pretty much across the board and then
secondly I wanted to see factor
volatility in the volatility stuff come
down to indicate that people were either
a hedged or they had taken their gross
down. Now I had seen the data that the
gross was down but
we obviously got
almost all of that. So
on the queues I posted this in X but the
four-day rally which included one day
last week and the first two days of this
week ended up getting close to 10% and
you can see that over the course of the
last 17 years since the great financial
crisis ended you can see these days over
time uh
and a lot of these are obviously very
famous bottoms in terms of liberation
day and obviously COVID
also this one here in 2022.
This one here
was a let's say a bear market rally in
early 2022. The difference was then
we were below the 200-day moving
average. This is something I brought up
before bull markets stay above the
200-day moving average which is pointed
upward. That's what we did in 80 plus
percent of the AI thematic names which
is why to me I was looking for where to
put money to work. That's why we went
through it that way. In terms of the S&P
rate of change four-day rate of change
the biggest one over the last year of 6%
and just to give you an idea how vicious
that rally was, we had been trading in a
range. So, every week that I came in
here, I kept saying the same thing,
which is this is a pennant flag
formation, whatever you want. And to get
bearish charts like this is a very
dangerous thing, but in particular when
you're seeing Qs fall and you're seeing
factor stuff collapse, you're looking
for contagion on this, which is very
difficult to happen when
you have earnings growth at
post-recession type times. Well, I'm not
going to go through all of it you guys
had, but the range that we were in
basically from May
to July. So, we're talking about 1 to
almost 3 months, a 3-month pennant.
And guess what? The rally we had was 6%
bigger than the entire range that we saw
for that time period.
That is not something to fade. Um
the S&P for the week up 3.6%.
Qs up 5%.
The thematic portfolio was up 6 and 1/2.
It was the second biggest week of the
year.
In terms of where we stand year-to-date
now in the S&P, again, I'll say this
over and over again, this is a bull
market.
Every sector is up on the year. The S&P
is up 13%.
Pennant formation
in there for a solid 3 months
breakout higher than this. We not only
hold after the Monday Tuesday, we make
new all-time highs
today.
IWM made new all-time highs this week.
New York Stock Exchange Composite made
new all-time highs this week.
The equal-weight S&P made new all-time
highs this week.
In terms of the KOSPI cuz I had a lot of
people reaching out saying this is still
a problem there. This is not a problem.
The KOSPI is up 61% year-to-date. This
is the KOSPI 200.
>> [clears throat]
>> The technology sector is up 116%.
This is after a collapse, okay? And I'm
not going to go through today, but on
days now where SK Hynix is down
slightly,
the name the sectors that I showed, the
machinery and the construction side,
have
been um leading on the way up and
holding their gains. So, again, this is
what long short is about. You get
deleveraging on both sides and at some
point you
start to go the other direction.
This is the DAX breaking out to new
all-time highs.
This is the FTSE breaking out to new
Here's the big thing for the week. So, I
showed you guys this. This is the
market-neutral momentum. This is the uh
So, this is the sector-neutralized
market momentum. This is market
momentum. This is technology momentum,
and this is the industrials momentum.
And if you look at all of these, the
last 6 days,
the drop-off in volatility says that
funds are hedged.
Here is the
7-day realized vol of the tech
momentum [clears throat] vol.
Uh basically collapsing,
which is indicative of what I just
showed. But, the what the main point is
that we've seen factor volatility drop
off. That is usually what happens after
this. And as I've said, it takes a long
time, particularly when you're below the
200-day moving average. You've knocked
people out. Um anyone that's vol
targeted just cannot lever back up. Any
of the pods that were hurt, that had
their risk management either reduced,
it's the summertime. This is why we're
going to rally on lower volume,
and everyone is going to be put in a
position of chasing. They don't want to
chase, they're going to read about
seasonality, they're going to read about
September, they're going to read about
the midterms and all of this stuff.
And in my opinion, I've heard enough
podcasts this week from quote-unquote
market people who
are in the game, I think, of being
bearish. Uh
they remain bearish in the rally and
they're looking for a false breakout.
So, we'll see if we get that, but
this is really hard to be bearish on
this stuff when this is going on.
Um the VIXY Q for single name ball
has fallen sharply, too, and it's
basically in this period now all the way
back to where it was before this whole
thing
rallied. Not where the panic started,
but where it goes. So, we've seen mean
reversion now on the ball side. In terms
of the VIX,
you're at the lows since January. So,
for everyone who reached out to me
saying the contagion was coming, they
were buying S&P puts,
uh
you not only lost on the direction, you
lost on the ball and the ball never
really in was indicative of the panic
that we saw with factor volatility at at
45-year highs on some measures.
Uh we never got it in the S&P.
CDX, um
I talked last week about the silliness
in the hyperscalers and how the
companies with the best balance sheets,
people are
looking at their CDS uh and especially
when they go into X. Here's what the CDX
index did, basically the same as the
VIX.
There's no credit issues at all.
Earning season, uh I'm not going to show
you this number, but you know it's up
near 50% in terms of earnings growth.
Sales growth, though,
uh
we're just killing it.
Killing it.
And as you'll notice, this is across
sectors. Um the AI trade from an
earnings basis is just taking everyone
up with it. Here's the revenue growth
now up at 15% and I just want you to
look that since Q1 of 25
basically this has gone on. Now, what
happened in Q1 of 25?
Donald Trump took over as president and
sentiment changed on the business side.
He put tariffs
in place. Everyone got worried, but the
AI trade was now in full force.
Uh and that's what is driving this. This
is the certainty over the AI CapEx. So,
these are the CapEx numbers basically
driving this. It's having a huge impact.
Margins
last year at this point 13%. This year
17%. And again, not just technology, it
is
margins are increasing and as AI
adoption and AI agents go, you're going
to see more of this.
Uh the breadth
again, I highlighted last week that it
was a good sign that we basically had
two prints higher than these two
and we followed through this week.
The 50-day is up to the highest level
since July 14th and most importantly
the 200-day slope
80 plus percent pointed upward.
Uh this has been the best quarter for
years
in terms of the earnings
estimates beats.
If you don't believe um
well, when I If you don't believe the
earnings
then look at the revenues. They continue
to move higher and this is the PMI which
soared higher. I can remember it was a
year ago PMI was below 50. I was writing
papers on the
PMI heading up towards 60 and what that
would mean all on the back of the AI
trade. Now, it's fairly consensus, but
we're almost at 60 now and more
importantly
uh
this implies that we're going to get
closer to it. So, we continue to move
higher, revs keep going up, and we got
durable goods this week, non-defense ex-
air,
again, up at a level that
is very close to 60. So,
again, for anyone who has faded this,
it's not just the earnings reports now,
you're seeing it at the PMI level,
you're seeing it global stock markets
around the world, and you're still
seeing revisions go higher.
Here is the AI thematic portfolio with
all four parts. Remember, you've got the
Morgan Stanley one here overlaid with my
100 name one. The Morgan Stanley one was
just created later. For those of you
want to trade it, you can call up Morgan
Stanley desk, they have it. You've got
the concentrated portfolio, which has 10
names, and then the more global
concentrated portfolio, which has 25.
Again, these were put together so that
you can have an index.
I think if everyone learned anything,
the indexes are really important when
you have this much volatility. So,
I want to get into the hedging side down
some of the conversation. So, I showed
this slide last week. Uh I believe the
market is changing structurally, and
this is never going back to the way it
was before, because AI is compressing
economic time.
Um I think you're going to see that with
the rest of the year. I'm going to go
through the payroll numbers from
yesterday, and I want you to reach out
to every one of your favorite economists
and ask them
why they're not seeing the weakness.
This is not about people um necessarily
being replaced by jobs. This is not
about jobs being lost,
but this is about wages. This is about
the fact that digital employees are
here, and they're coming
incredibly quickly, because the adoption
pace is picking up. I'm going to take
you through Palantir, which is um
a name that I own personally, but also a
name in the model portfolio,
which just showed their corporate
numbers. Since we can't get Anthropic
and OpenAI in terms of numbers that
we're getting released, you can look at
Palantir's. These numbers are insane in
terms of the adoption. When the adoption
picks up, the AI agents are going to
come and the AI agents come, not only
are you going to have less hiring, you
will start to see more job losses in
public companies. You'll have job
creation in private AI native companies,
which I'll go through. Terminal value
gets harder to ask to estimate, which
makes it more difficult that companies
all of a sudden can go from trading at a
30 PE to a 20 PE in a very short amount
of time. We've seen that in many many
places and I think you're going to
continue to see it. I think Google's
kind of going through that right now. Um
I won't read all of these, but all of
these things, including this one, which
Gavin Baker brought up, too.
The the fact that everyone
has access to it and everyone can create
a backtest, everyone can create an
optimized portfolio, everyone can find
the names that are working, leads to
more momentum, it leads to crowding. And
again, it leads to bubbles, parabolas,
and speed crashes. Exactly what we had
this year, what I wrote about. The speed
crash has occurred, it's over. The
bottom is in as far as I'm concerned on
a probability basis. If we take out the
lows, I'd be surprised, uh mainly
because I continue to believe people are
way too bearish relative to the reality
of the earnings growth that's coming. I
also don't believe you're going to ever
see that type of move again uh that we
saw in the first quarter, but you never
know. So, with that hedging side, how do
you deal with bubble bubbles, parabolas,
and speed crashes?
Well, those are all based on
price and time, which I started to show
you last week, but I'm going to go
through one of the demos in terms of how
I how I'm handling this. And for the
subscribers, this will become part of
the way that I'm going to identify
things. I built turbulence models. The
turbulence models because everything was
so correlated, they never really showed
leading problems. The breadth did, and
that's how I'm going to kind of go
through this. So, I try to learn from
what happens and look for the signals
that will warn you. This is one signal
that will warn you when factor vol
continues to move higher and break away
from index vol. The reason factor vol is
is so much different than say single
name equity vol, which also broke away
and I showed last week,
this has got a long short component of
it and this is directly related to gross
leverage. So, the great thing about
factors are as gross leverage is going
to all-time highs and I'm making the
call that we are at peak gross leverage
and that we will see leverage come down
over the course of the next few years
because of what I showed before that AI
is compressing time, it's making it more
crowded and it means the sharp ratio of
this stuff is going to come down. I
think factor vol is structurally going
to be higher. I don't think we're going
back down here. Maybe we come back down
into 25, but if we spend now the rest of
this year in the 30 to 25. And again,
this is an equal weight of four separate
factors. It's not just momentum because
I have value in there, I have quality
and I have beta. And so, I'm averaging
them all in there. You can see the
difference in the breakaway from the
S&P, which means using index
puts is not going to work the way that
it used to.
So, here's what I am using and this is
the price in time side. So, right here
when we when we got to 50% or almost
50%. This is a 50-day rate of change on
my thematic portfolio. So, again, for
those of you on the AI side that are
more tech focused or you're more
industrial focused or you're more
utility,
you need this tool. You need to have
access to this data and the reason is
because there are no indices that are
diversified to this level. This is
global. This is across sectors. This
involves 100 names that are involved in
there. There are chemicals, power
companies, industrial companies. So, it
is diversified.
50% move
over 50 days. So, 50 trading days, which
means slightly more than 2 months. To be
up 50% you're going to fall. Now, here
is the historical levels. At 20% I think
the risk grows and I think that's when
you need to combine it with
this.
These happen to peak at the exact same
time.
So, rate of change does not mean that
the thematic trade goes down. It just
means you start to run in. So, I've
always used rate of change. In the past,
before we had exponential
uh innovation, in 2007 my model gave a
recession
uh warning or not it gave a recession
signal in September of '07.
So,
in September of '07 is when the warning
went out that we were going to have a
recession. And the reason was because
year-over-year S&P, the 252-day rate of
change of the S&P,
had basically started to turn negative.
Once that happens, historically, that
means we're at a bad point. When you add
in corporate profits, you add in jobless
claims, again, this is before
exponential AI or before exponential
innovation with software. So, for me,
this is the way that I'm replacing this.
I'm looking for
the rate of change to be up at a level
which doesn't make sense, which shows
the crowding, it shows the AI agents, it
shows everyone pushing everything. And
then I'm looking for breath to be
breaking down within inside the 100
names. You need a diversified portfolio.
So, this is the way I'm going to measure
it. I gave you guys the warnings back
here. We didn't make a high in the index
until right around here.
Then we didn't violently fall on the
memory names and stuff here. So, I
talked about selling Micron in here.
This is when I got rid of all of it. It
was early.
I rotated to silver, to Bitcoin, and to
Eli Lilly, and to some other names.
The main point was those names in the
month of July, go look what they did.
Silver and Bitcoin
Well, silver was flatish. Bitcoin was up
a good amount. Lilly was up. You're
trying to navigate where you're still in
a position to buy when you get the puke.
So, this is the way it looks and this is
the way I'm going to go through it. This
is the whole year actually.
It's the It's the rate of change. So,
once you break above
this level, then the warning sign
starts. So, we broke above this level.
We started peaking in terms of the
the breadth, we were up at 90% believe
it or not. We're above the 20-day moving
average and then gradually we broke
down. You can see how this goes. Now,
the four-week average peaked here and
rolled over. So, as time goes on, I
believe this is going to happen now more
often and I think this is the way you're
going to have to deal with it.
I've had a lot of subscribers reach out
about a bunch of names that just haven't
bounced yet. Things like Camurus, I own
this one. Fluence, I own this one.
Entegris did go higher. I own this one
and Palantir, I didn't include the price
today. It's all the way up here now.
For all the Palantir haters and all the
short people and the people that go,
you're missing something on this one.
It's the only software name I own
personally and then you've got Cadence
and Synopsys that are part of the
the thematic portfolio that are software
design. I'll probably be talking about
them soon
because there's been some stuff. So,
that's the way that I'm kind of working
through with people to automate things
on the hedging side, to use my index for
that, but also to use the breadth and to
use the different parts. This is the
thing I was saying on an earnings
mosaic. So, what I did create and the
prompt will go up over the weekend.
I created a prompt for you guys that
will basically spit out something like
this. You can use it in Gemini. You can
use it in ChatGPT,
but basically this will use and this is
to give you a sense where if you take my
technical sheet and you update you put
the technical sheet into chat GPT
and then or Claude or Gemini or
whichever one you want Grok and then you
just run the prompt it will go out and
get the earnings commentary from the
week and put it together with a bunch of
different things including kind of a
look at a mosaic side. So this was from
Eaton you had Eaton report this week.
You also had Schneider report. They're
both on the electric side. They both
happen to be participants in Vera Rubin.
So it will go through and it will look
at and give you basically a recap of
that with some of the most important
commentary that was in there. I'm trying
to help you guys especially as times
were goes so this is what it does. This
is what you'll see up there.
I'm trying to keep you guys going with
the AI side. Again, if you guys want to
access to the tools, if you want access
reach out to Mark Wailing, go to the
website.
We're doing more and more of these but
in particular I'm doing more and more
presentations for RIAs where I'm also
doing regular calls with them. They're
setting things up that way so you can
reach out to Mark. I did want to
reference this because this is where we
we are in the agentic side. This is a a
a text
exchange with my son. Uh
he's a entering his junior year at
college. He is not a computer science
major. He I put him through
Python boot camp when he was a junior in
high school.
I have my AI chief of staff spitting out
new sub agents on the regular. This is
what he's doing at his internship.
He even said I prefer chat GPT Gemini
coding is insane though. I got the
information from YouTube and AI.
Your kids have to be doing this guys. He
is guaranteed to have a job at whatever
firm he works because he has already
built a chief of staff. He's spitting
out those new sub agents. There's
absolutely no reason
why your kids can't do this. So remember
the knowledge brain thing that I put in
there, I will be doing AI agent stuff
for the subscribers. I will probably be
going through some videos
as we get into this year. I got a lot
going on with the crypto side, but my
goal is to really make sure that you
guys realize that the agentic side is
here and if you're not using it, you're
falling way behind. So, let's go through
the Gavin Baker side. Again, this is a
must listen. The reason it's a must
listen is cuz very seldom do you find
someone who is this knowledgeable about
the AI trade from a very high level,
which Gavin is. He speaks about it
regularly. He's asked questions on it
regularly. He invests in it. It's very
hard to find people that know this from
the industrial side all the way out.
I'm not going to read all these up. I'm
just going to go through the speaker
argues the AI sell-off is disconnected
from the quantitative data. He says he
has not found a real negative demand
metric.
So, I just want to make sure that you
guys, if you listen to this,
if you just listen to the first 5
minutes of this,
these are all quotes from the first 5
minutes.
Nvidia actually, as we record this, is
at the lowest forward PE of the last 10
years.
I've bought a decent amount of Nvidia
over the course of the last 3 weeks. It
looked good for a while, broke back down
again, now it's looking better.
I believe with Vera Rubin coming out and
with all the chatter on this and the
fact that it's this cheap, but also
going through the token per watt needs
and realizing how quickly they're
they're coming out with this stuff, I
just can't see a sign with what GPUs are
doing, the price of them which he goes
through,
that they're not going to benefit from
this at this level. So, they've done
their multiple compression, it's been
significant.
I just it's it's not it's not going to
double for you, I'm sure, in in in a
short amount of time, but I think when
you're looking at kind of safer names
that already have seen their multiple
compressed, I still think Nvidia is one
of the best ones. Um
not a single instance of deceleration,
nothing. In fact, every metric rate is
accelerating. Whether you cut GPU
availability, whether you cut GPU rental
pricing, whether you cut the spot price
of DRAM this month to grow, everything
is actually accelerated.
So, when you go through all of these and
you hear what he says about Anthropic
and you hear what he says about deep
compute prices and the anecdotal stuff
that he gets out there.
I He's basically saying that these
companies
Microsoft, Meta, Amazon, the
hyperscalers, the critical part of this
because if you've been bearish on them,
which most people have, they've called
this a bubble, they've been wrong.
They've said ROIC will not come through,
they've been wrong.
Maybe they'll be right. The CDS is wider
for justified reasons cuz they're still
leveraging up more and more and I'll go
through the reason why it does make
sense in a second, but
you can't argue the fact that at this
point there's a chance that they could
see significant revenue very short-term
if for no other reason because they are
building so much compute and the value
of that compute is going up and he talks
about it here.
The same type of B200 cluster that
rented around mid $2 per hour 7 months
ago is now expected to rent for just
under $4 per
GPU hour. So, remember all the stuff
about these chips won't survive, their
lifespan. We have a bottleneck in
compute.
So, you have to go through all compute
has value right now regardless of where
it is. Open source would love to be
using this stuff. So, let's just
forget all the stuff that you've heard
on this.
Don't get all bearish on this because of
something that isn't true by the data.
If you see this data start not to happen
and that's what he goes through,
it's like the breath that I have on the
index. If one thing is going down,
that's fine, but when people look at the
token index and that's their thing and I
say on this video, even the people at
the place that provided say it's not
bearish on
on market. It just means more and more
of the usage is going on open source,
which makes sense.
It doesn't mean it's bearish. It doesn't
mean that Anthropic's revenues aren't
going to grow, but very smart people
that I've known in the business for a
long time were saying that to me. So,
we've had a point that if you can listen
to someone like him and go through it,
it's there.
It's rewiring the market structure. So,
he got into the same thing that I talked
about.
He even brought up the probabilistic
Bayesian interpretation of the future,
which I write about all the time and I
talk about all the time.
AI compresses economic time, but it it
may also compress market time.
The month of July
for momentum was worse than any year
over the data that I have.
So, that's how we're compressing market
time. Bubbles, parabolas, and speed
crashes.
Here are the key quotes from the
transcript. You guys
can pause it and look at it on your own,
but here's the most important one. We
are in a cute compute shortage.
And at the same time, 500,000 people,
maybe 250,000 are using a generative AI.
So, my son is one of them. He's spinning
out sub-agents.
But only 250,000 of 8 billion people.
What happens when we go from 500,000 to
1%? To 100 million? To 500 million?
Guys, I say it all the time.
There will never be enough compute,
ever. We will continually be building
compute. We'll be doing it in different
ways. We'll continue to get more
efficiency. Everything will keep
happening, but nothing is on the horizon
for that to go away. So, when we see the
prices of GPUs on older stuff start to
head down, at least we're at a point
where the newer stuff is saturating some
of the demand ahead of adoption, but the
adoption is happening because of agents.
And once you set them off, they're
tireless workers. So, it is exponential
against
the physical side. No amount will ever
be enough. The math behind hyperscaler
CapEx. This is my post earnings paper
that went out this week
on the hyperscalers and the reason why
you should not be playing for them to
break apart.
Now,
I got a lot of questions saying does
this mean you're bullish on
hyperscalers? No, not relative to the
infrastructure trade. Nothing changes in
that front. I still think they're going
to have heavy competition, and here's
the other reason why.
The hyperscalers quarterly free cash
flow, when we think they're going to go
positive as a group by Goldman Sachs.
Look how long this is out. So, here's
the problem.
They're going to keep spending money on
hoping they get the revenues in the
door.
I I understand they have the cloud
revenues, but the cloud revenues are not
going to be enough in my opinion. You're
going to need to have products, you're
going to have need to have other things,
or you're going to get priced like a
utility or real estate company, cuz
eventually, when the compute isn't
as
outsized in terms of supply versus
demand as it is now, and by then we
could have a lot of innovations. We
could have a lot of things on the
algorithmic side. Things could change.
There could be breakthroughs in hardware
that when we go to uh humanoids and we
go to cars and we go to all this,
everything could change. Now,
I still believe we're going to need more
compute, we're going to need more
hardware, but
whether their businesses will be there
is a question, and that's why their
multiples should be compressed, and
their CDS should be
wider. It There's a risk there. So,
it's [clears throat] not a
a a risk that I want to
go out there and trade, but if you're
buying their paper
and you want to
buy some CD I of course you do. If
you're trying to short the AI trade and
you want some stuff out there, of course
you go buy CDS in this, especially when
it just keeps moving. Um I just want to
bring this up quickly cuz I think
[clears throat] this is a sign about the
problem inside these companies. So, I
also believe that this is a big deal
what happened this week with Jeff Dean
leaving.
And also, Demis Hassabis kind of moving
into another area.
This is a big deal to me and this is
because Google is the perfect example of
a company where
they released AlphaFold,
which makes them no money.
If it makes them some money, it's coming
through something, but for the amount of
people using it to release it free,
it's probably created some conflicts
inside cuz they are spending tons of
money, they're taking tons of debt. They
need actual consumer products,
corporation, they need something to come
through and I think this is where the
people who are trying to leave a legacy
on this technology, the talent, are
getting frustrated with the bureaucracy
at big companies. And I think you're
going to see this over and over again.
It's reason why I'm negative on all
public companies by the time we get to
2030, the bureaucracy is going to be a
killer. At the same time, you're going
to have AI native companies growing
rapidly.
Okay, I just want to remind you on the
memory side. I wrote this paper
is in June, AI equals memory. This is
after I had sold my Micron. This was not
to buy anything. This was just to let
people know that memory will remain in a
shortage and it is something to watch
when it comes to the trade, but it's
also something to watch closely to see
if we ever get to the point where
catches up to compute. So, on the SpaceX
earnings call,
Elon Musk
basically reiterated what I wrote in
that paper. The limiting factor
currently is memory. The memory output
is increasing by around 20% a year. So,
supply is increasing by about 20% a
year. The demand is increasing by 200% a
year, maybe higher.
If you've got demand increasing faster
than supply, economics 101 would suggest
the price increases.
Uh again, I'm bringing this up because
watch memory.
And this goes through more compute does
not solve the bottleneck without more
memory. So, the memory side is going to
be needed and that's what I wrote about
is that memory is needed for all parts
of this when you start thinking about
what AI agents need, but especially when
you get into consumer agents, we need
lots of memory on everything that we do.
Palantir shares jump on uh
otherworldly sales improved forecast.
This is what I was saying. This is
commercial revenue. This is the adoption
side of companies.
This is the growth rate. 54%, 64%. These
are year-over-year. They're not only
growing by this much,
they're still growing faster.
So, 149%.
So, in Q2 last year, they had 306
million of revenue. This year, it's 764.
So, whether it's quarter-over-quarter
growing at 20-plus percent or whether
it's
it doesn't matter. These guys are
growing rapidly. And everyone is focused
on them and commercial was not their
business. So, it's starting from a small
pace. This just shows the adoption pace
that's going. They closed on 220 deals
of at least 1 million, 98 deals of at
least 5 million, and 78 deals of at
least
10 million.
Only reason I brought this up is to just
show you that the bear porn just remains
out there.
Here are new business formations.
This is what the story is, guys. This is
AI native companies. They're starting
their own businesses. That's what I did.
This is how This is what's happening.
It's going parabolic with AI adoption.
All started with Opus 4.5.
The rise of million-dollar companies
with just one employee. So, this is
what's happening to disrupt the profits
of the Fortune 500 companies eventually.
It will take some time because these are
small, but it's coming.
The age of abundant intelligence and
scarce Bitcoin. Two printing presses
running at once. One dilutes the unit
you measure wealth in.
That is the debasement of your money.
The other dilutes the durability of the
corporate claims you bought into to
protect that wealth. So, this one is
from the government and the printing
press.
This is the AI printing press, which
will disrupt public companies.
That's in my Substack.
Okay, 30-year yields. So, I put this
line here cuz basically we took it out.
This was a big story.
Um
I'm writing a paper right now on the
JGBs
as the widow maker from the 1990s.
And how every time
I get a technical chart or a person
saying we just broke out, this is going
to collapse,
rates are moving higher,
stocks pretty much almost always rally.
Now,
the reason is
cuz the government doesn't really have a
choice. So, if you're going to fight
something
and you want to be bearish on the
equities because of bonds, the
government, if the bond yields go too
high,
they clearly are going to do something.
They've done it repeatedly. We know
that. They did that on liberation day.
Okay, we don't care if equities go down.
Then when the bond market went down,
they cared that equities went down and
they had to do something. Here is the
relationship between corporate tax
receipts
and household
equities
asset values.
If you have asset values go down in
stock market, you're going to have tax
receipts go down at a time when we have
5 to 6% deficits. That's why Lyn Alden
wrote about why nothing stops this
fiscal train. It is still in place, guy,
and we learn more about it this week
because it's not just the US, it's the
whole globe. So, when you see these
charts and you got the US and you got
the UK and you got JGBs and you even got
bonds.
They're all 30-year yields around highs
of some level and what did happen so on
Friday night Scott Bessent has to
explain why he helped Japan strengthen
the yen.
So, I believe this is more a signal.
Um Scott's obviously a savvy market
person and he's trying to find a way to
help the BOJ for a variety of reasons
and one of the reasons is because they
own a lot of treasuries and he doesn't
want them to have to go in the market to
sell the treasuries to be able to go out
and
buy the yen.
So,
first coordinated move since 1998.
Long view, US props up the yen to
support treasuries.
Then Bessent is urging the Fed to help
defend the Japanese yen using
FEMA and hoping to expand the capacity
of it. So, then you got the Wall Street
Journal and Nick
Timiraos
Why Bessent is leaning on the Fed to
help prop up Japan's currency. I want
you to remember that cuz last week Kevin
Warsh spoke. So, last week you had
situational awareness. You had Kevin
Warsh. Market got angry at Kevin Warsh
cuz he didn't either raise rates or he
didn't say he was going to raise rates,
he gave no guidance. Nobody knows what
to do. He didn't even say
I think we're kind of getting the sense
here that uh it's going to be really
hard for Warsh to raise rates if the
Fed's going in to help Japan and we need
interest rate differentials there and
he's actually going to the Fed and
trying to see if they can raise the
borrowing limit. Seems like the Treasury
and the Fed might be a little closer
than um they used to be.
Uh then we go through and we're starting
to talk about the unintended
consequences and I think
I think the joint US
Japan support at the end is unusual. The
way it is being financed is
unprecedented and adds liquidity when
the punch bowl of the US economy and
markets is already overflowing.
And he pledged to do whatever it takes
to help.
Again, I think the bazooka he doesn't
want to do anything, but I think he's
hoping we can stay away from 164 and
maybe they'll raise rates in September,
but if Warsh raises rates in September,
then what does it really accomplish,
which is one of the reasons why
I'm shocked after this last 2 weeks that
we still have a 45% chance of a rate
hike in September, which is why I like
all the debasement trades, as I talked
about a few weeks ago, thinking that
people were getting way too over their
skis on rate hikes.
Remember, a lot of places were talking
about three, at least two, before the
end of the year and now I'm now we still
have one in change in there. We'll see
where it goes. Uh, the policy fails to
tackle the underlying problem can easily
backfire. Not least drawing the Federal
Reserve into exchange rate policy at an
especially awkward moment. That's the
awkward moment what I'm talking about.
Um,
Treasury has now spent all the ammo in
their exchange stabilization fund.
They can probably find other ways, but
unless interest rate differentials
change, it's all waste. So, we're back
to the interest rate differentials.
Then a former ex former Japan PM warns
FX action won't save yen without 2.3
trillion growth strategy. This is the
run it hot into a scarcity of tools that
the central banks can use. Can the US
Treasury save the yen?
Kevin Warsh is facing more than a
communication problem. Um,
I wanted to bring this up again because
I think last week
was a big week. Situational awareness,
Kevin Warsh not raising rates,
and then the Fed doing what they did
with the BOJ, the first coordinated move
since 1998.
I think with all of that at the end of a
historic month where we had deleveraging
of significant size, there's a lot of
similarities between October of '98 in
there, a lot of them. And I believe when
we look back as long as those lows are
in place that that will be a time that
we started to see a reality check
that when the US is intervening in the
Japanese currency market to help their
treasury market, the fiat system might
be in trouble. Uh
especially when I go through some of the
charts. So, we're 45% as of Friday for
the Fed to raise
rates, and and that's after the payroll
number. And we're at 63% for the BOJ.
Uh Darius Dale put this out on the
quarterly refunding,
the Fed has little choice but to
continue monetizing US sovereign debt
over time. The Basically, the refunding
announcement, there's
whatever Kevin Warsh people thought he
was,
again, this is why why nothing stops
this fiscal train. It is we just have
too big a debt, too big a deficit.
Remember when Paul Tudor Jones went on
and did the math and said there's just
no way to solve this. They're running it
hot, but they're not making any impact.
So, here we go.
During Donald Trump's tenure as
president,
July was the biggest 30-year
yield rise in a month.
So, back here is when he drew the line
in the sand for the equity market. So,
here's what happens to the S&P after the
bond market ends up going higher.
Bond market goes higher, guess what?
Oh, you're starting to get the picture
here. So, the S&P has rallied when rates
go higher because everyone starts
getting bearish on it and the Fed or the
Treasury needs to step in. Nothing stops
this train. We keep doing the same
thing. So,
gold is waking up that maybe Warsh is
not going to be bad for gold. Maybe he's
not going to raise rates. So, gold
over the course of the last 16 years, it
was the third biggest week for gold.
Now,
this was
one of the largest printing press weeks
of all time.
This is when gold was out of control.
This is a big week in gold, up 7.2%.
Here's the chart. Broke through the
50-day. Look how long we were below the
50-day. We broke below the 50-day
over here. We hadn't been back above
since March. In fact,
it was the third longest time that we
had been below the 50-day moving
average. Now,
here are the returns 3 months out from
the time of breaking back above. We'll
see what this one is.
But, year-over-year at the break point,
most of the time these things were down
big.
Gold's in a bull market. So, again, I go
back to what I said before.
When you're in a bull market and you
correct and then you consolidate and
then you break back above the 50-day,
things can run pretty hard. I think
there is an absolute reason
to be thinking that gold, silver,
platinum, Bitcoin, all of them, assuming
that the Fed is not going to cut rates
in September,
which again, I'm surprised we have 45%.
We'll see what happens with the
inflation data next week, but I think
we're getting closer and closer to this
and the market is telling you the
signals where people like, well, why
don't I just short Treasuries and go buy
gold and go buy this? I think either way
right now,
I'm going to win because they're going
to come in and stop it, but I don't
think it can go down. So, here's what we
got. Platinum breaks above the 50-day.
And again,
nice rounding chart. We'll see if
there's follow-through. Silver finally
closed above the 50-day today. I have a
good-sized position in silver because of
the AI side, but I like it now because
of the the basement side. I showed this
last week.
We're at the highest dollar long
position. So, the dollar has already
broken down, but this is just fuel for
the fire for gold and
and silver and platinum and Bitcoin. And
again, just a reminder, still 44%, not
just that, we still have more
tightenings in.
I I think there's I mean, I think all of
these should be coming out, personally.
That's just me. And the reason is
this inflation thing is driving me nuts.
We have one inflation data point, which
is upward. Um
this is the Truflation core number
relative to the CPI core number. You
cannot get away from the fact that it
has led and it has gone.
This is a violent move lower over the
course of the last 4 weeks. So, the
year-over-year Truflation number just
continues to fall. This is on the same
scale, people. So, where this was around
the same at the beginning of the year,
you've had a slight uptick here, and
you've had this collapse. Go read how
they do their work.
If Kevin Warsh is looking for better
data points than just taking the way
something was calculated 50 years ago,
at least give Truflation a chance, along
with trim mean, along with the other
ones that I've shown. I think the
inflation thing is a disaster. So, let's
go the other way.
I'm sick of economists and the payroll
side.
The job situation is not good.
Yes, there are low claims. And the
reason there's low claims, part of this
is the labor force is coming down, but
they never talk about that. So, the
supply of labor is going down because
the labor force participation rate is
coming down sharply, has come down
sharply this year. Well, if there's less
labor supply, shouldn't that mean wages
are going higher?
Here are the wages.
So, this is the quits rate and the
Atlanta Fed wage side. On both measures,
we are back to 2019 levels. You can't
tell me the labor market is good with
those metrics. Let's just take the
average hourly earnings that we just
got, which is now down to 3.2%. It's
also the white line is also where it was
before 2020.
Overlay it again with the Atlanta Fed
median wage growth, right here.
You can't tell me the labor market is
good.
Let's go a different route. Let's now
take the aggregate payrolls.
This is the aggregate payrolls,
which is taking weekly hours, average
hourly earnings, and the number of job
creation. I've talked about the fact
that the only jobs that have been
created over the last 18 months are in
healthcare. When you strip out
healthcare, there is no job creation.
That is not a good jobs market. AI
agents are have or AI is having an
impact on hiring. It's not yet had an
impact on firing, but again, if we're
having job creation with entrepreneurs,
and we're gradually losing people on the
other side, which is the way I think it
goes,
I I don't think we're ever going to see
big job losses. I think the demographics
will kick in, we'll see more people
retire, the stock market as it goes
higher, more people say, "I don't need
this anymore. I've made enough money."
So, here is the last 6 months. Just look
at these 6 months, guys,
and take it back over time. This is a
very weak period, and if you want to see
really how weak it is, and again,
this is the weakest 6-month rate of
change
on the aggregate weekly payrolls
going all the way back to 2012
when you throw out the COVID time
period. I don't care how you measure
this. Maybe it'll change, but right now
the data is a fact.
The number of people looking for work
and the number of people counted as
unemployed both fell.
We're losing people in the labor force.
This is 10-year yields, the 20-month
moving average,
which is at 4.29,
and we're currently up here.
Here's the labor force participation
rate.
As more people leave the labor force,
rates should be coming down.
That's it. So, we'll see what happens,
but again, we've got the rise of the
million-dollar companies happening now,
so I think the
future of the job situation will remain
weaker because AI agents are coming.
It's not that they're going to collapse,
but I think people are making a huge
mistake not understanding that these
little tiny companies that have no
employees will be replacing bigger
companies
with maybe 50 employees, 100 employees.
And when those when that company closes,
those people have to recycle in. I just
think the quits rate, all of that stuff
is showing what's happening much better
than what your economists are telling
you. And so, at some point here, I do
think we're going to see weakness either
A in inflation or B inside the job
market driven by AI, which surprises
people.
So, here we are. Bitcoin is still in a
bear market until we get above there.
Anything from my perspective is a
trading side. So, I'm going to I I think
this is going to hold, and I think we're
going to break out. But as of right now,
we haven't. But there is some good news.
I want you to go read this because I do
believe that this is the most important
time because of the agent to kick in.
But what I really like is as the agent
and my crypto 40 name index,
the ecosystem is doing well.
We just saw the Clarity Act basically
over the course of the last 2 weeks go
from about 33 to 40 uh let's say 3 weeks
ago, we were getting close to 50. We
collapsed to 17%
chance that it gets signed into law this
year.
We also had strategy Michael Saylor sell
more.
And we also had
cold card exploit. And if you guys
didn't see this, there was even a, you
know, a pretty big story on cold storage
problem with one company
uh and people's wallets. And yet, all
that going on mm
Bitcoin was okay this week.
That's it for me this week, guys. Uh
keep enjoying your summer. Reach out to
Mark Whaling. Reach out to me.
Uh and we'll keep going through it. But
uh let's make some money
uh starting now for the rest of the
year. See you.